<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Anohba Jehad</title>
    <link>http://localhost:36033/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Anohba Jehad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 11:00:00 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:36033/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Trust Your Code—Test It</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36033/posts/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 11:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36033/posts/test/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-testing-your-code-matters&#34;&gt;Why Testing Your Code Matters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we write code, we want it to work. But sometimes, it doesn’t. That’s where &lt;strong&gt;testing&lt;/strong&gt; comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Testing helps us check if our code is doing what we want. It tells us if something is broken, so we can fix it early — before it becomes a big problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-should-we-test&#34;&gt;Why Should We Test?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you make a function that adds two numbers. You think it works. But what if it doesn’t? You don’t want to find out later, when everything depends on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Logging In Python!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36033/posts/pythonlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 12:30:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36033/posts/pythonlog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Logging is a means of tracking events that happen when some software runs. It is an essential aspect of software development that helps in debugging, monitoring, and maintaining applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python provides a built-in logging module that makes it easy to track events and errors in your code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-logging&#34;&gt;Why Use Logging?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many beginners use print() statements for debugging, logging provides a better way to record messages, debug issues, and monitor applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crafting with Hugo: a Lightning-Fast Site Generator🔧!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36033/posts/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 12:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36033/posts/hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to crafting ultra-fast and secure static websites, Hugo emerges as a top contender. Its blend of speed, simplicity, and powerful features allows users to build exceptional websites without the complexity of traditional web development workflows. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into Hugo&amp;rsquo;s core benefits and walk you through deploying your site seamlessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-hugo-is-a-game-changer&#34;&gt;Why Hugo is a Game-Changer&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re wondering why Hugo stands out, here are some key reasons:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
