<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Shell on Anohba Jehad</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/shell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shell on Anohba Jehad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.148.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 12:15:56 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oh My Zsh!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/zsh/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 12:15:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/zsh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Zsh isn’t just a shell—it’s your terminal’s upgrade to first class.&amp;rdquo;
If you&amp;rsquo;re someone who spends time in the terminal—whether you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, a student learning CLI, or a curious explorer—your shell environment is more than just text on black. It&amp;rsquo;s your workspace, your command center, your vibe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-zsh&#34;&gt;What is Zsh?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zsh (Z Shell)&lt;/strong&gt; is a powerful, interactive shell and scripting language for Unix-like systems. It’s like Bash’s cooler, more customizable sibling—think of it as Bash after a glow-up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shell Shocked? Try Fish!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 12:15:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fish/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to shells, most of us are familiar with Bash, the default shell in many Linux distributions. However, for those looking for a more user-friendly, modern experience, Fish Shell is a great alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-fish-shell&#34;&gt;What is Fish Shell?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fish, which stands for Friendly Interactive Shell, is a user-friendly shell designed to be easy to use and understand for both beginners and advanced users. Unlike other shells like Bash, Zsh, or Tcsh, Fish prioritizes simplicity, intuitive features, and efficiency. It’s often regarded as one of the most modern shells for Linux and macOS systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
