<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu on Anohba Jehad</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ubuntu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu on Anohba Jehad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 12:30:00 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ubuntu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dijkstra&#39;s Algorithm: Your GPS for the World of Graphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/dijkstra/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 12:30:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/dijkstra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dijkstra’s Algorithm is a popular and efficient algorithm used for finding the shortest path from a single source node to all other nodes in a weighted graph. It is widely used in network routing, mapping applications, and many areas of computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-dijkstras-algorithm&#34;&gt;What Is Dijkstra’s Algorithm?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dijkstra’s Algorithm solves the single-source shortest path problem in a graph with &lt;strong&gt;non-negative edge weights&lt;/strong&gt;. It finds the shortest path from a starting node (source) to every other node in the graph.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master GitHub: A Beginner’s Guide to GitHub CLI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/githubcli/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 12:30:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/githubcli/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitHub CLI (Command Line Interface) is a powerful tool that allows developers to interact with GitHub directly from the terminal. Whether you want to create repositories, manage pull requests, or handle issues, GitHub CLI makes the process seamless and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-github-cli&#34;&gt;Why Use GitHub CLI?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with the command line, GitHub CLI eliminates the need to switch between your browser and terminal. It integrates well with Git, making repository management faster and more intuitive. Some benefits include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install and Configure SSH on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 12:30:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ssh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-ssh&#34;&gt;Introduction to SSH&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSH (Secure Shell) is a tool used to safely connect to remote computers and servers. It encrypts data, keeping your connection secure from hackers. Developers and system administrators use SSH for tasks like remote access, file transfers, and running commands on distant systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-of-ssh&#34;&gt;Advantages of SSH&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secure Communication – Encrypts data, preventing eavesdropping and attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remote Access – Manage servers and systems from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key-Based Authentication – Enables password-free and more secure logins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Vim: A Developer`s Swiss Army Knife</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/vim/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/vim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vim is more than just a text editor; it&amp;rsquo;s a powerful, lightweight, and highly customizable tool that can significantly enhance your productivity. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a developer, system administrator, or just a curious enthusiast, learning Vim can be a game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide will introduce you to Vim, covering its basic commands, modes, customization options, installation, and essential plugins to optimize your workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-installing-vim&#34;&gt;1. Installing Vim&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive in, let&amp;rsquo;s install Vim on your system:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
