<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ubuntu CLI on Anohba Jehad</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ubuntu-cli/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ubuntu CLI on Anohba Jehad</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:30:56 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ubuntu-cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Git-ing It Together: Git Good with Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:30:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/github/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ever felt like your code projects are a chaotic mess, with random files named &amp;ldquo;final_version_final_FINAL&amp;rdquo;? Don’t worry, you’re not alone! Enter Git and GitHub, the dynamic duo that’s here to save your projects from utter disarray. Let’s break them down in the simplest way possible, so you can join the cool kids and say things like, “I’ll just push it to GitHub.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-git&#34;&gt;What is Git&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Picture this:&lt;/strong&gt; You’re writing a novel, and every time you make changes, you wish you had a backup of the previous version. What if your brilliant idea turns out to be total garbage?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub&#39;s Personal Access Token: Your Key to Secure Access</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 12:30:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-personal-access-token&#34;&gt;What Is a Personal Access Token?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Think of a Personal Access Token as a secret key or a VIP pass that gives you access to your GitHub account. Unlike passwords, which are meant for logging into the GitHub website, PATs are used for command-line operations (like pushing code) and integrations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why use them? Because PATs are more secure! Even if someone gets hold of your token, you can easily revoke it without changing your GitHub password.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avoid the Gates of Hell. Install Linux. </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 12:55:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;linux&#34;&gt;LINUX&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Linux is a best-known, versatile and most used open-source operating system initially developed by Linus Torvalds in 1991 as a &amp;lsquo;hobby&amp;rsquo;. There are many distributions or distros (different organizations and communities create their own versions e.g Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora etc.) of Linux, which include different software options. This means that Linux is incredibly customizable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ubuntu&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ubuntu was used after the African philosopher translated it to “Humanity to Other”. Ubuntu has been derived from Debian’s architecture and the Linux server. It is  free of cost and comes with a built-in firewall system and user-friendly interface. With Ubuntu, you do not need to worry about hackers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
