<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Algorithm on Anohba Jehad</title>
    <link>http://localhost:36033/tags/algorithm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Algorithm on Anohba Jehad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.147.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:46:56 +0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:36033/tags/algorithm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Huffman Coding: The Art of Compression</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36033/posts/huffman/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:46:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36033/posts/huffman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a world drowning in data, how do we store and transmit information more efficiently? The answer lies in &lt;em&gt;Huffman Coding&lt;/em&gt; — a beautifully simple yet powerful algorithm used for &lt;strong&gt;lossless data compression&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s been a cornerstone since it was introduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-huffman-coding&#34;&gt;What Is Huffman Coding?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huffman Coding is a &lt;strong&gt;greedy algorithm&lt;/strong&gt; used to compress data without losing any information. The idea is simple:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Assign shorter codes to more frequent characters and longer codes to less frequent ones.&lt;/strong&gt;
Ever tried zipping a file to save space? That magic trick behind the scenes? That’s compression — and Huffman Coding is one of the smartest ways to pull it off.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dijkstra&#39;s Algorithm: Your GPS for the World of Graphs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:36033/posts/dijkstra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:46:56 +0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:36033/posts/dijkstra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dijkstra’s Algorithm is a popular and efficient algorithm used for finding the shortest path from a single source node to all other nodes in a weighted graph. It is widely used in network routing, mapping applications, and many areas of computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-dijkstras-algorithm&#34;&gt;What Is Dijkstra’s Algorithm?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dijkstra’s Algorithm solves the single-source shortest path problem in a graph with &lt;strong&gt;non-negative edge weights&lt;/strong&gt;. It finds the shortest path from a starting node (source) to every other node in the graph.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
